Come out, one of the twelve disciples...
（ｱﾝｼﾞｪﾚﾈ）
来たれ 十二使徒のひとつ
（ｱﾝｼﾞｪﾚﾈ）危ない！
（ｼｽﾀｰＡ）アッ…
Sister Angelene!
（ﾙﾁｱ）シスター･アンジェレネ！
（上条(かみじょう)）あっ…
Sister Angelene!
（ﾙﾁｱ）
シスター･アンジェレネ！
Man...
（建宮(たてみや)）
…たく
Don't show me something as pathetic as that!
（建宮）
心の底から つまんねえもんを
見せんじゃねえのよ！
これを使え
Here, use this.
What is it?
（ﾙﾁｱ）これは？
（建宮）脱出用の上下艦ってやつよ
An escape pod.
It's a better alternative than staying here.
（建宮）
敵地の真ん中よりは
マシだろう
Sister Lucia, your hand's shaking...
（ｱﾝｼﾞｪﾚﾈ）
シスター･ルチア 手が震えてますよ
Of course it is.
（ﾙﾁｱ）
当たり前でしょう
Come on, I'm not going to die here.
イヤだな
こんな所で死ぬはずがないのに
We'll all go back together, right?
（アンジェレネ）
みんなで帰るんですよね
You... as well as everyone else fighting here...
シスター･アニェーゼも
そして あそこで
戦っている人たちも―
Everyone will be together...
本当の意味で
みんな一緒に
That's why I won't die.
だったら
私は死にません
So, please... fight your hardest to protect everyone...
だから お願いします
みんなを守るために
一緒に戦ってくれませんか？
Say something, Lucia.
（上条）
断言しろよ ルチア
I'll help if possible.
（上条）
その手伝いができるなら 俺は―
Even if it means destroying as many
of these stupid illusions as I have to.
こんな くそつまらねえ幻想なんて
いくらでも ぶち壊してやる
So say something that will make her think it was worth being here.
（上条）
だから 断言しろよ
こいつが今 ここにいて
良かったなって思える ひと言を
Something that will make her believe it was worth gritting her teeth!
歯を食いしばるだけの
価値があったんだって
信じられる ひと言を
（ルチア）
はい
Yes.
I'll protect everyone, no matter what.
必ず皆を守ってみせます
So, please, you have your own fight right now.
だから あなたも―
自分自身と
戦ってください
#16 Appointed Time
of the Rosary
Are they still at it?!
（ビアージオ）
まだ鎮まらないか？
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
まったく… たかだか
町をひとつ つぶすのに―
Sheesh.
I didn't think we'd have to go through
so much trouble just to sink one city.
ここまで手間取るとはな
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）フッ… その顔
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）あっ…
That face...
Absolutely wonderful.
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
たまらんな
この期に及んで まだ―
That expression that says you still believe in them.
ずうずうしく
誰かに期待してる表情が
And what would I believe in?
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）
私が何に すがるですって？
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
フン！
I'm going to break your hopes now.
君の希望をここで打ち砕く
You've no need for such emotions.
部品に感情は必要ない
Go!
行け！　何が何でも
あの子を連れ出してこい！
Get that girl at all costs!
ンッ…
行くぞ インデックス オルソラ！
Let's go, Index, Orsola!
Nobody seems to be here.
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
誰も いないようでございますね
This ship is most likely monitoring the entire fleet using magic.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
多分 この船が魔術的に
全ての船を集中管理しているんだよ
That'd explain why the Sisters haven't followed us.
（上条）
だから シスターたちも
追いかけてこないのか
Just a moment.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
待ってて　今 鍵を解いてみるから
I'll unlock it.
I'm starting to get a little tired of thinking things through!
そろそろ こっちも
いろいろ考えるのが―
面倒になってきたっつうの！
What was that?
（上条）何だ？　こりゃ
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）ブロック構造だね
A block structure.
Unlike the escort ships, this ship has
magic embedded throughout its structure.
護衛艦と違って 船全体に魔術的な
意味を持たせているからかも
Those knights...
（上条）
さっきの鎧(よろい)か　くそ！
Crap!
Go inside.
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）中へ！
（上条）えっ？　おい ちょっと！
W-Wait!
You guys go on ahead!
（上条）
お前たちは先に行け！
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻(とうま)！
（上条）ウオーッ！
Touma!
Sister Angelene, are you all right?
シスター･アンジェレネ
無事ですか？
Yes, I'm fine.
（ｱﾝｼﾞｪﾚﾈ）
はい 大丈夫です
If they weren't my comrades...
（ﾙﾁｱ）
しかし どう切り抜ければ…
Sheesh.
（建宮）…たく
（ﾙﾁｱ）あっ…
How boring.
（建宮）つまんねえな
（ｼｽﾀｰたち）あっ…
Stop picking on the injured girl.
（建宮）
ケガ人相手に遊んでんじゃねえのよ
Crap, another one!
くそ… 行き止まりかよ！
This is...
（上条）
ここは？
うわ… また来た！
Another one?!
Is that all?
終わったか？
It connected!
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
つながったのでございますよ
オルソラか？
Orsola?
Touma, is it true that, to activate The Queen of The Adriatic Sea,
当麻 “アドリア海の女王”の
発動条件に―
they need to cast another spell called
"Appointed Time of the Rosary"?
“刻限のロザリオ”って別の術式が
必要っていうのは本当？
Something like that.
（上条）
そうらしいけど…
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
私の10万3,000冊には―
My 103,000 grimoires say nothing about that!
それが必要って記述は
ひとつもないんだよ
Then what kind of a spell is it?
じゃ 一体 どういう術式なんだ？
I think it's a codename only known by
members of the Roman Catholic Church.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
ローマ正教内部だけに伝わる
計画名みたいなものだと思う
ハアッ！
（能力の発動音）
ハァ…
That right hand...
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）その右手…
（上条）あっ…
フッ… 羨ましいか
Do you like it?
Not one bit.
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
承服できないね
主の恵みを拒絶する…
そんな性質も さることながら―
Not only does it cancel out the blessing of the Lord,
but you swing it around like it's some sort of weapon.
それを武器として
振り回すというのが 何よりも
If you had ever heard God's teachings,
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
一度でも
御言葉(みことば)を耳にしたのなら―
then you would do anything to receive his
blessings, even if you had to rip your arm off!
即座に 腕を引きちぎってでも―
恵みを得ようと努力するのが
筋だというのに
I suppose the language of humans would
make no sense to a pagan monkey.
所詮は異教の猿に
人の言葉は通じないか
In that case, I, Biagio Buzoni, will put an end to this enemy of the Lord.
ならば
このビアージオ＝ブゾーニが―
主の敵に引導を渡そう
So you're Biagio?
てめえがビアージオか
That means you know where Agnese is.
なら アニェーゼの居場所も
知ってんだな
Knowing and telling are two very different things.
知っているのと教えるのとは
全く別物だがね
The cross is the way of repentance!
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
十字架は悪性の拒絶を示す
The cross can eliminate enemies, as well
as provide a safe zone anywhere near it.
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
外敵を廃し
内部に安全地帯を作るための―
役割を十字架は持つ　このようにな
Just like this.
Additionally, the cross also holds the
power to correct a man of his pride.
一方で十字架は
その重きにおいて―
人のおごりを直す性質を持つ
Again... just like this.
それも また
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）このように
（上条）あっ…
Where am I?
ここは？
Now, now...
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
おいおい あまり壊してくれるなよ
Must you break everything around you?
You might affect the purity of the spell.
向こうの完成度に影響が出るのでな
What do you mean?
向こうだと？
The Appointed Time of the Rosary.
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
刻限のロザリオだ
Don't pretend you know nothing of it.
この期に及んで
知らぬとは言わせない
It doesn't matter. This will be over if I
crush you and get Agnese out of here.
（上条）
ともあれ てめえをつぶして―
アニェーゼを引っ張ってくりゃ
それで終わりだ
Are you really going against the will of the Lord?
主の意向に反する意思を示すとは
悪い言葉だ
Such evil words.
My crosses will reject that evil.
その悪性は
我が十字架が拒絶する！
ンンッ… くそったれが
Damn it!
You think you have the right to do whatever you want with Venice?!
てめえにヴェネチアを
どうこうするだけの特権が―
あるとでも思ってんのか！
That is not my intention.
私のねらいは そこではない
なんだと？
What did you say?
At the very least, it's a hundred times more
interesting than what you're thinking.
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
少なくとも
君が考えているよりは―
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）ず～っと面白い
（上条）ンンッ…
Do you know what the oldest execution tool in Christianity is?
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
十字教にとって最も重要であり―
最古の使用法は何だと思う？
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
ハハッ… 処刑の道具だよ
Execution tool, I said.
Simon bears the cross of the Son of God!
シモンは神の子の十字架を背負う
What the...
何が…
The cross is the way of repentance!
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
十字架は悪性の拒絶を示す
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
ここは？
This is...
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
あっ… 防御術式が仕込まれてる
There's a defensive spell on it.
C.A.H.
Shift focus onto me
（インデックス）
ＣＡＨ
Go get Agnese!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）あなたはアニェーゼを
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）あっ…
I'll keep these guys busy!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
こっちは私が引き付けるから！
Index-san?!
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
インデックスさん！
Orsola Aquinas?
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）オルソラ＝アクィナス…
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）よくご無事で
Thank goodness you're safe.
Why are you here?
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）
なんでですか？
Did you not want to escape The Queen's Fleet?
あれだけ女王艦隊から
逃げたがっていたじゃないですか
Don't you know what you're getting yourself into?!
今が どんな状況か
全部 分かってんでしょう？
Once we understood the situation at
hand, not one person wished to flee.
分かっていれば誰だって ここから
逃げようなどとは言いませんでした
They did not wish to leave you as a sacrifice and run away.
皆を助けるために
口をつぐんだ あなたを置いて―
自分たちだけ立ち去ろうなどと
That's not right.
変ですよ
You remember what I did for The Book of the Law, don't you?
「法の書」を巡って
私が何をやったか覚えてんでしょう
How can you just save me after everything we've been through?!
あそこまで やられておいて
なんで水になんか流せんですか？
I, myself, do not know why.
その答えは私には分かりません
But Lucia and Angelene-san swore to save you.
ですが 少なくとも
ルチアとアンジェレネさんは―
あなたを助けたいと断言しました
Even in the midst of a desperate situation,
たとえ絶望的な状況を
目の当たりにしても―
and even when they had an infinite number of blades pointing at them.
無数の刃(やいば)を
突きつけられたとしても―
They wanted to save you.
それでも もう一度 皆と笑いたいと
告げた彼女たちの言葉に―
Is that not enough of a reason?
まだ足りないと
思っているのでございますか？
It's no use, Sister Agnese.
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
困るんだよ シスター･アニェーゼ
Even if you die here, the operation will go on as planned.
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
たとえ 君が ここで死んでも
計画は途切れん
But finding another compatible person is such a tedious task.
しかし また ほかの適正者を
探すのは面倒くさいだろう
And I really hate things that are tedious.
私は面倒くさいのは
大嫌いなんだ
That blood...
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
その血は…
面倒くさいのは嫌いだと言ったろう
I said I hate tedious things.
So I crushed him in the quickest manner possible.
だから 手っとり早く つぶしてきた
I'd rather not have to do it again here.
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
できれば ここでは避けてほしいな
I can't have you hurt for our plan.
安易に 傷をつけられてもらっては
困るのでね
The anti-Venice large-scale spell...
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
対ヴェネチア用大規模術式…
そんなものを なぜ今更？
Why are you activating it now?
We're not trying to use the anti-government attack.
私たちが行おうとしているのは
対国家用の攻撃術式ではない
その先にあるものだ
It's something beyond that.
The Queen of the Adriatic Sea is a spell
made only to be used against Venice.
“アドリア海の女王”は―
対ヴェネチア用にだけ
作られた術式だ
どれだけ魅力的な威力を
誇っていても―
No matter how compelling it seems, if we can't
undo the lock-on limitation, then it has no point.
照準制限を解けないかぎりは
意味がない
Then why...
ならば なぜ… あっ…
It seems you've realized.
そうだ　気づいたな？
We're undoing the lock-on limitation
of The Queen of the Adriatic Sea.
“アドリア海の女王”の
照準制限を解く
That's what The Appointed Time of the Rosary is for.
そのための刻限のロザリオだ
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
まさか あなたたちは―
Are you saying that you plan to destroy all cities that are in your way?
ジャマと感じた都市を破壊すると
おっしゃるのでございますか？
The Queen of the Adriatic Sea destroys
everything connected to the city!
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
“アドリア海の女王”は
その都市に関わった全てを破壊する
What do you think would happen if we aimed
it at the city where the enemy kingdom lies?
それと同じことを 敵対する世界を
束ねる都市に向かって―
放てば どうなると思う
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
まさか 学園都市を？
Academy City?!
あらゆる科学技術は
学園都市の影響を受けている
All kinds of science are connected to Academy City's technology.
If we destroy it, we can destroy everything that has to
do with the other half of the world in a single night!
それを全て破壊するとなれば―
いまいましくも 世界の半分を
包み込んでいるサイド全体を―
一夜にして
駆逐することができるのだよ
Do you think that will make everyone happy?
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
それで皆が 幸せになるとでも？
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
思わんよ
Not at all.
害なす者は魔術サイドの中にもいる
I know that there are evildoers on the magic side.
But they can continue whatever they were doing.
しかし 続ければよい
いずれ 不純物は取り除かれる
Eventually, all those impurities will be eliminated.
あなたは…
Do you—
That's what the Roman Catholic Church wishes for.
それが悲願なのだよ
ローマ正教のな
The cross is the way of repentance!
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
十字架は悪性の拒絶を示す
ハハッ…
やめておけ シスター･オルソラ
Just stop, Sister Orsola.
十字架は
その重きをもって おごりを正す
The burden of the cross chastises the proud!
Now then, we're ahead of schedule, but
how about we start this, Sister Agnese?
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
さて 少し早いが始めるか
シスター･アニェーゼ
Rejoice!
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
喜べ　君は十字教の歴史上―
You will go down in history as the one who eradicated
the largest number of enemies to Christianity in history!
最も多くの敵を葬った名誉を得る
Those "enemies" you speak of...
その あなたが語る敵の中には
アニェーゼさんも―
They include Agnese, don't they?
含まれているのでは
ございませんか？
You fear because you now belong to the Church of England.
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
今の君は
本当にイギリス清教なのだな
だから焦る
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
あなたは本当に―
You really can't act on anything but suspicion, can you?
猜疑心(さいぎしん)でしか
動けないのでございますね
You don't understand what it means to act on hope.
人が思いで動くということを
理解できない
Or, though you do understand, you cannot bring yourself to believe it.
いえ 理解はできても信じられない
Please move.
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）どいてください
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）あっ…
There's no way you can stop Biagio.
どのみち あなたに
ビアージオは止められません
If you don't stand up to him you can make it out of here alive.
抵抗さえしなければ
きっと死なずに済みます
そんなことが
できるわけがないでしょう！
I can't do that!
This is the end, Sister Orsola.
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
終わりだ シスター･オルソラ
笑え シスター･アニェーゼ
Too bad, Sister Agnese.
君の夢が砕けるさまを眺めて
Both your dreams are about to be crushed.
何のマネだ？
What is the meaning of this?
All things correspond with each other.
万物照応　五大の素(もと)の第五
Of the five elements, one of the fifth.
The symbol of peace and order.
平和と秩序の象徴 司教杖(しきょうじょう)を展開
Expand the Bishop's Staff!
Sister Agnese!
シスター･アニェーゼ
何のマネだと聞いているのだ？
I asked you what the meaning of this was!
フン！　あなたの疑問どおりですよ
What do you think?
I'm probably wrong.
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）
間違ってんでしょうね
こんな私が―
I'm wrong to want to continue taking care of
Sister Lucia, Sister Angelene, and the rest.
まだシスター･ルチアや
シスター･アンジェレネたちの―
面倒を見たいなんて思っちまうのは
When I think of all the Sisters who are out
there, fighting because of your stupid order...
あなたのクソみてえな命令で―
戦わされているシスターたちを
思って 憤ったりすんのも
It makes my blood boil.
Don't speak as if you're so high and mighty, you sinner!
ナメた口を利いてんじゃねえぞ
罪人が！
Simon bears the cross of the Son of God!
シモンは神の子の十字架を背負う！
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）フフッ…
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）確か 神の子は―
If my memory serves correctly, the Son of God did not
have the strength to carry the cross himself.
十字架を背負うだけの体力は
残されていなかったはず
Simon carried it up the hill for the execution instead!
彼に代わって シモンが十字架を
処刑場の丘まで運んだ
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）違いますか？
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）気づいたか
Am I wrong?
You realized it?
The true form of this attack is in
making the enemy bear a heavy weight!
装備品の重量を肩代わりさせる
それが この攻撃の正体です
おおかた ここで働いている人間の
装備品の重量を集めて―
You focus the weight of all the personnel and
equipment here onto one point and turn it into weight.
攻撃力に変換している
…といったところですか
Something like that, right?
That weak hand of yours can't do anything.
そんな軟弱な手で…
You're going to need a stronger hand.
やるなら
もっと頑丈な腕を用意しろ
（上条）そうかよ
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）うん？
Really?
Then how about this right hand?
（上条）
じゃ
こんな右手とかならいいのか？
Why, you...
貴様… 異教の猿が！
You pagan monkey!
Next time, at least make sure I'm dead.
死体くらいは確認しとけよ マヌケ
My right hand isn't as easy to beat as you think!
てめえが思ってるより
俺の右手は―
甘くなんかねえんだよ！
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）ンンッ…
（上条）遅(おせ)え！
Too slow!
Like that'd work on me twice!
同じ手を食うか！
（上条）
ンッ… アニェーゼ
Agnese.
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）
はい
Yes?
Thank you.
（上条）ありがとうな
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）あっ…
If you hadn't protected Orsola, things would have gotten a lot worse.
（上条）
お前がオルソラを
守ってくれなかったら―
きっと大変なことになっていた
Oh...
（上条）あらら　フフッ…
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）フフッ…
So, how do we go about destroying
The Queen of the Adriatic Sea entirely?
…で “アドリア海の女王”全体を
ぶっ壊すには―
どうすればいいんだ？
Well, this room can't be changed.
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）
え～っと… この部屋だけは
替えが利かねえそうです
If we completely destroy its functions, they can never reconstruct—
ここの機能を完璧(かんぺき)に破壊できれば
もう二度と…
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）アアッ！
（上条）アニェーゼ！
Agnese!
Agnese! What's wrong?!
（上条）
アニェーゼ どうした？　あっ…
The Appointed Time of the Rosary...
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
刻限のロザリオ… まさか それが？
Is that...
霊装を介して アニェーゼさんに
何かしたのでございますか？
He's activated it and has done something to Agnese!
フッ…
使えんよ 未調整のままではな
I can't use it without proper adjustments.
だが 力だけなら既に ここにある
But I have all the power I need right here.
The Roman Catholic Church feared that the
weapon might be stolen and turned against us,
ローマ正教は これを奪われて―
自分たちに向けられることを
恐れたがゆえに―
so all those restrictions and limits were put into place.
さまざまな手を加えた
So if it ever did fall into the hands of the enemy,
what do you think their last resort would be?
ならば 敵に渡ってしまった際―
最後の手段として
何を用意していたと思う？
あっ… 自爆か！
A self-destruct?
This is a large-scale magical tool supported
alchemically by this entire fleet of sinners.
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
こいつは
この艦隊の罪人どもが―
錬金的な方法で
補強した大規模魔術装置だ
Don't go thinking that simply destroying the walls or floors can stop it.
壁や床を砕いた程度で
とどまるなどとは思うなよ
With the sheer amount of magic in here, the
explosion will be at least 10 kilometers wide...
術式が暴発すれば 爆発力だけでも
半径10キロは下らないはずです
There will be casualties on land, too!
そうすれば 湾岸にも被害が
（ｱﾆｪｰｾﾞ）ウウッ！
（上条）アニェーゼ！
Agnese!
ウワッ！　アアッ…
Orsola, take Agnese and get out of here!
（上条）
オルソラ
アニェーゼを連れて先に行け
天草(あまくさ)式の連中も引き揚げさせろ
Get the Amakusa people to leave, too!
でも あなたさまは？
But what about you?
あいつを止めるしかねえだろう
I have to stop him.
I promise I'll meet up with you later.
あとで必ず合流する
だから行け オルソラ！
Just go, Orsola!
But...
（ｵﾙｿﾗ）
そんな…
It's a promise!
絶対… 絶対でございますよ
That bastard...
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
あの野郎…
"Carve your name into Roman Catholic history," my ass!
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
なにが
“ローマ正教の歴史に残る大義”だ
I told him it was too early for a plan like this!
だから
私は早すぎると言っていたのに…
I'm done for.
私は もうおしまいだ
So you're going to take down everything with you?
だから 全てを巻き込むのか？
結局 てめえがやってるのは
ただの慰めじゃねえか
In the end all you want to do is console yourself!
Nobody wouldn't feel that this situation is dangerous!
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
これだけの状況に
危機感を覚えぬ者などいない
これは もはやローマ正教の脅威だ
This is the ultimate will of the Roman Catholic Church.
Anyone would agree with my decision.
誰もが私の選択に納得する
最後に花を添えるのだよ
This is the last flower that will bloom in my life.
I will gladly destroy the coast of the Adriatic Sea for that goal.
そのためならば アドリア海など
くれてやればよいのだ
（上条）
ビアージオ
Biagio!
That look!
その顔だ
その不屈こそが我々の脅威なのだよ
That look of persistence is exactly what threatens us!
だからこそ
ここで確実に つぶしておく
And that is why I will be sure to destroy you here.
That will be my final legacy to the Roman Catholic Church!
それが 私がローマ正教にささげる
最後の貢献だ！
ビアージオ！
Biagio!
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
十字架は悪性の拒絶を示す
The cross is the way of repentance!
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
十字架は
その重きをもって おごりを正す
The burden of the cross chastises the proud!
The cross is the way of repentance!
十字架は悪性の拒絶を示す
ウワッ！
Is Sister Agnese such a great prize for all this?
シスター･アニェーゼ単品が
それほど有意義な報酬か？
There is no longer any safe harbor for that woman.
既に
あの女を迎えてくれる場所など―
どこにもないのだ
Why don't you understand that, you pagan monkey?!
それが なんで分からねえんだよ？
異教の くそ猿が！
Who needs to understand that?!
（上条）
分かってたまるか！
Who'd accept that?!
くそったれが！
The cross is the way of repentance!
十字架は悪性の拒絶を示す！
ビアージオ！
Biagio!
His left hand?!
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）左手？
（殴る音）
He used my own attack?!
（ﾋﾞｱｰｼﾞｵ）
こいつ 私の攻撃を利用し…
Of course I'll fight.
（上条）
戦ってやるよ
If you dare lay a finger on Agnese again,
てめえらが またアニェーゼたちを
狙うってんなら―
I'll beat you down to a pulp.
俺は何度でも刃向かってやる
Hey, Touma!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻 当麻！
（上条）うん？
Have you come to?
あっ 気がついた？
アドリア海って
そんなに冷たくなかったよね
The Adriatic Sea isn't all that cold, huh?
うん？　なんで お前
そんなに うれしそうなんだよ？
Why do you look so happy?
Is it because I didn't abandon you this time?
まさか 今回は
置いてけぼりにされなかったから？
はぁ？　べ… 別に
ご機嫌なんかじゃないもん！
I-It's not like I'm happy or anything...
You have a phone call, Touma.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻 電話だって
（上条）うん？
Come back to Academy City right now.
（ｶｴﾙ医者）
君 今すぐ
学園都市に戻ってくるんだ
It would be troublesome for other
facilities to be poking around your body.
（ｶｴﾙ医者）
やっぱり 君の体を外の病院で
調べたりするのは ちょっとね
There should be a supersonic jet sitting
around in the Academy City airport.
（ｶｴﾙ医者）
空港に学園都市製の―
超音速旅客機が
止まっているはずだから
（上条）
ま… まだイタリアに来て
１日しか たってな…
But I haven't even been in Italy for a whole day—
（ｶｴﾙ医者）
ああ そうそう
見舞い客の女の子が―
Oh, right!
Some girl came looking for you earlier and left a message.
君に
是非 伝えてほしいことがあると
"When you get back, be prepared for
the penalty game from the Daihaseisai."
（ｶｴﾙ医者）
“帰ってきたら―”
“大覇星(だいはせい)祭の罰ゲームは
覚悟しなさい”だってさ
Misaka Mikoto?!
（上条）
御坂美琴(みさか みこと)！
Wai— Let go of me!
ちょ… 放して　帰りたくない～！
I don't want to go back!
I see.
（神裂(かんざき)）
そうですか ご苦労さまです
Thanks for your help.
（土御門(つちみかど)）
にゃ～…　つうか―
And you should really ask the Amakusa people
rather than me if you want a debriefing.
結果報告なら
天草式に尋ねろっつうの
hitori de ii to tsubuyaita toaru sekai no chuushin de
In the center of a certain world, I whispered "I'm okay by myself"
（神裂）
今の私は もう天草式の
人間ではありませんし
I'm no longer associated with the Amakusa Church...
tokei no hari wo orimagete hitomi tojiteta
I closed my eyes as the hands of the clock turned
True as that is, you sure dragged Kami-yan
into a lot of trouble again, Nee-chin.
（土御門）
それはそうと ねーちん
今回も カミやんに―
大迷惑を
かけちまったにゃ
（神裂）あっ…
（土御門）こりゃ既に
At this point, even serving him as his personal maid
for a whole day wouldn't be enough to cover it!
メイド服で
１日ご奉仕程度じゃ―
収まりが つかないぜ
sugisatta toki wa modosenai kedo
We can't bring back the past
Oh, hey, why don't I lend you the fallen
angel maid battle costume I have?
そうだ！
俺が持ってる―
堕天使メイドセットを
貸す
それで勝負に出ろよ
ねーちん！
You can use that as your battle outfit!
ano hi oshietekureta yo ne
But you told me that day
ど…
どこまでバカげたことを
What kind of ridiculous crap are you talking about?
sore de iin da to
"It's okay this way"
大体 あなたは
そんな物を―
And why do you have something like that anyway?!
所持しているのですか？
You're one of only 20 Saints in the
world. I'm sure you're prepared for—
（土御門）
ああん？
仮にも
世界で20人もいない―
meguri meguru kisetsu ni kimi ga ita kiseki
In the passing seasons, with the miracle of you being there for me
聖人だってんなら―
覚悟を決めろよ ねー…
（電話を切る音）
kowareteta tokei sae ugokidasu kara
Even the broken clock begins to move again
ima wa sou muryoku na garakuta dakedo
And though I may not be powerful now
fushigi da ne kaerareru sonna ki ga suru
It's strange how I feel that I can go back
な… なのですよ 当麻
L-Like this, Touma...
kimi no koe ga ima mo mada koko ni aru kara
Even now, I can still hear your voice right next to me
I-I'm back.
た…
ただいまでございますよ
I accidentally picked up more luggage on the way back.
実は 途中で荷物が―
増えちゃったので
ございますよ
But that was a bit rushed.
（ﾛｰﾏ教皇）
しかしな あれは少々 早急に過ぎた
Who do you think you're talking to?
（ｳﾞｪﾝﾄ）
あんた 誰に もの言ってんのよ？
Do you understand who it is you're running your mouth off at?
（ﾛｰﾏ教皇）
貴様こそ誰に口を利いているか
理解は追いついてるのか？
（ｳﾞｪﾝﾄ）
ローマ教皇でしょう
そんなことが どうしたの？
The Pope.
What of it?
If you treat me badly, you're going to die!
私に悪意を向ければ
あんたは死ぬわよ　シャー…
The Right Seat of God...
神の右席
教皇程度では響かぬか
The title of Pope means nothing to you, does it?
Read this and sign it.
こいつに目を通して
サインをしなさい
You're giving me an order?
（ﾛｰﾏ教皇）
この私に命令か
なっ… 待て この書類は…
W-Wait, this document is...
You were planning on issuing the order yourself at some point, no?
あんたも いずれは
命令するつもりだったことでしょう
（ﾛｰﾏ教皇）
う～む…
Kmaijou Touma. Investigate this individual immediately.
If he is confirmed as an enemy of God, eliminate him.
Next Episode
（上条）
穏やかに秋を迎える学園都市
Autumn quietly arrives in Academy City.
One promise destroys those peaceful days.
その平和な日常を切り裂く
ひとつの約束
What's transpiring?
果たして 何が起きるのか？
Next time: "Penalty Game."
次回 「罰ゲーム」
When science and magic cross paths, this epic will begin!
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる